

FEDERICO OTÁLVARES

UX DESIGNER & FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

Hello! I'm Fede, a UX Designer and fullstack developer. With a passion for design, I enjoy creating intuitive and engaging digital experiences. My extensive knowledge in web development allows me to create functional solutions from front-end to back-end. Throughout my extensive teaching experience, I have developed effective communication skills and empathy, enabling me to understand the needs and priorities of users. My approach and ability to combine aesthetics and functionality make me a unique and versatile profile in the world of design and development.

CONTACT

in fedeotalvares-ux-dev

EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGNER AND FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

2023 - Present

Freelance projects of UX design and frontend web development.

TEACHER AT SECONDARY SCHOOL

2014 - 2023 | Liceo Egara

Teacher of Secondary Education in the subjects of ICT, Computer Science, Robotics and Audiovisual in the 1st to 4th secondary courses.

EDTECH RESPONSIBLE

2015 - 2023 | Liceo Egara

TAC manager with the functions of:

- Advice, implementation and use of technology
- Teacher training.
- Implementation, administration and management of the GSuite platform for education.
- Design of didactic and informative material.

SERVICE DESK TECHNICIAN

2010 - 2013 | T-Systems

Experienced administrator and technical support providing services to clients such as the Government of Catalonia, Correos, and Seat.

EDUCATION

FULL STACK DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP

Frontend and Backend developer

ISDI Coders in Barcelona

UX DESIGNER

Google UX Design Certificate

GRADUATED PRIMARY SCHOOL TEACHER

Graduated in Primary Education with mention in ICT in education.

(International University of Valencia)

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR TECHNICIAN

Higher degree in computer systems administrationCSSF (Barcelona)